<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-20T18:33:14+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Enterprise Data Science</title><subtitle>Entrprise Data Science the art to deliver value through data
</subtitle><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><entry><title type="html">AI Inclusion / Selection Bias Challenge</title><link href="/post/2020/12/20/AI_inclusion_challange.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI Inclusion / Selection Bias Challenge" /><published>2020-12-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-12-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/post/2020/12/20/AI_inclusion_challange</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/2020/12/20/AI_inclusion_challange.html">&lt;p&gt;Intelligence is the ability to learn from experience, solve problems, and use knowledge to adapt to new situations (David G. Myers, Psychology 12 Edition). I refer to artificial intelligence (AI) systems as a collection of advanced technologies that allow machines to sense, comprehend, act, and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine learning and statistical models are often within the heart of these AI or data-driven systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I experience three major pitfalls repeatedly when designing statistical / machine learning models for data-driven systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;not knowing the business value and definition of good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;selecting wrong or biased information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;designing models which are too complex and costly to maintain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following, I will only focus on the selection bias problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine learning systems and as well humans drive the learning through iterations with data/information. The quality, amount, preparation, and selection of data are critical to a machine learning solution’s success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One famous statement in machine learning is garbage in will lead to garbage out. Of course, I fully agree with this statement. However, often it is not clear what garbage is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are obvious issues related to data quality problems, like missing data or outliers even before we can judge the quality of data. We have to select a representative data set linked to your business application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any AI engine and as well every statistic calculates on the seen datasets.
However, every underlying dataset is the product of human decisions. Human biases occur within the selection and curation of data, which will show up in AI systems’ outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video summarizes an AI inclusion problem; it shows the biased output concerning the search term ‚family ‘.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a society or ethical perspective, it is a significant problem, often summarized as an AI inclusion problem. Note that the term AI inclusion many different aspects are typically discussed around development, social impact, policy implications, and legal issues concerning AI systems, see, e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://aiandinclusion.org&quot;&gt;aiandinclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically speaking, what happens in this video is a selection bias problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selection bias occurs when the samples used to produce the model are not fully representative of cases that the model may use in the future.
The selection bias comes not only within AI systems; it lies in the heart of any statistical evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a data-driven world, automated processes and decisions are based on statistical models. Thus, a basic understanding of statistics is mandatory to judge critically on results and outputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize a strong wish towards content featuring deep learning systems in my current data science lecture class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we have to teach the basics first before going fast into modeling. Within our data science education programs, we have to focus more on statistics and thus the judgment of AI systems instead of teaching fancy algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think - explicitly teaching the topic selection bias - would it help tackle the bigger AI inclusion problem?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="Ethics" /><summary type="html">Intelligence is the ability to learn from experience, solve problems, and use knowledge to adapt to new situations (David G. Myers, Psychology 12 Edition). I refer to artificial intelligence (AI) systems as a collection of advanced technologies that allow machines to sense, comprehend, act, and learn. Machine learning and statistical models are often within the heart of these AI or data-driven systems. I experience three major pitfalls repeatedly when designing statistical / machine learning models for data-driven systems. not knowing the business value and definition of good selecting wrong or biased information designing models which are too complex and costly to maintain In the following, I will only focus on the selection bias problem. Machine learning systems and as well humans drive the learning through iterations with data/information. The quality, amount, preparation, and selection of data are critical to a machine learning solution’s success. One famous statement in machine learning is garbage in will lead to garbage out. Of course, I fully agree with this statement. However, often it is not clear what garbage is. There are obvious issues related to data quality problems, like missing data or outliers even before we can judge the quality of data. We have to select a representative data set linked to your business application. Any AI engine and as well every statistic calculates on the seen datasets. However, every underlying dataset is the product of human decisions. Human biases occur within the selection and curation of data, which will show up in AI systems’ outputs. The video summarizes an AI inclusion problem; it shows the biased output concerning the search term ‚family ‘. From a society or ethical perspective, it is a significant problem, often summarized as an AI inclusion problem. Note that the term AI inclusion many different aspects are typically discussed around development, social impact, policy implications, and legal issues concerning AI systems, see, e.g., aiandinclusion Technically speaking, what happens in this video is a selection bias problem. Selection bias occurs when the samples used to produce the model are not fully representative of cases that the model may use in the future. The selection bias comes not only within AI systems; it lies in the heart of any statistical evaluation. In a data-driven world, automated processes and decisions are based on statistical models. Thus, a basic understanding of statistics is mandatory to judge critically on results and outputs. I realize a strong wish towards content featuring deep learning systems in my current data science lecture class. However, we have to teach the basics first before going fast into modeling. Within our data science education programs, we have to focus more on statistics and thus the judgment of AI systems instead of teaching fancy algorithms. What do you think - explicitly teaching the topic selection bias - would it help tackle the bigger AI inclusion problem?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Enterprise Data Science</title><link href="/docs/enterprise_data_science" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enterprise Data Science" /><published>2020-02-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/docs/Enterprise_Data_Science</id><content type="html" xml:base="/docs/enterprise_data_science">&lt;h3 id=&quot;enterprise-data-science&quot;&gt;Enterprise Data Science&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data science is the art of delivering value through data. Delivering this value to a customer often requires a complex interaction of business understanding, mathematics, and computer science practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An enterprise is defined as any human endeavor involving people, its purpose to serve a customer, where various kinds of platforms support each activity.
The customer value describes the heart of an enterprise objective while delivering the value is often done via services and products affecting humans and their environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprise data science is focusing on enterprises producing products and their related services. These enterprises often have a complex value chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A value chain is a set of activities that an enterprise performs to deliver a valuable product (i.e., good or service) for the market  (source wiki)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various definitions exist for a value chain, for simplicity, in this context it is defined with a focus on manufactured goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product Development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Procurement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supply Chain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manufacturing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marketing / Sales&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lifecycle management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customer Services
A value chain model describes the mechanism to execute the processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In each building block within a value chain, many decisions are carried out, most often by humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which product should we design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where to source the components&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Should we produce product A or B this week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much should I give a discount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Should we phase out the product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which customer to serve when and how&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have to make decisions over and over again, and each decision affects the future. Typically we distinguish between:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the strategic decisions with a focus on future years,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tactical decisions with a focus on the next months,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;operational decisions with a focus within the day or week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data science has the goal to support better decisions through data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supporting effective decisions through data means often supporting a human with the help of decision support systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supporting effective decision means most often the push towards automation or automation support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Enterprise data science supports effective and efficient decisions within a company’s value chain. **&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="B2B" /><summary type="html">Enterprise Data Science Data science is the art of delivering value through data. Delivering this value to a customer often requires a complex interaction of business understanding, mathematics, and computer science practice. An enterprise is defined as any human endeavor involving people, its purpose to serve a customer, where various kinds of platforms support each activity. The customer value describes the heart of an enterprise objective while delivering the value is often done via services and products affecting humans and their environment. Enterprise data science is focusing on enterprises producing products and their related services. These enterprises often have a complex value chain. A value chain is a set of activities that an enterprise performs to deliver a valuable product (i.e., good or service) for the market (source wiki) Various definitions exist for a value chain, for simplicity, in this context it is defined with a focus on manufactured goods. Product Development Procurement Supply Chain Manufacturing Marketing / Sales Lifecycle management Customer Services A value chain model describes the mechanism to execute the processes. In each building block within a value chain, many decisions are carried out, most often by humans. Which product should we design Where to source the components Should we produce product A or B this week How much should I give a discount Should we phase out the product Which customer to serve when and how We have to make decisions over and over again, and each decision affects the future. Typically we distinguish between: the strategic decisions with a focus on future years, tactical decisions with a focus on the next months, operational decisions with a focus within the day or week Data science has the goal to support better decisions through data. Supporting effective decisions through data means often supporting a human with the help of decision support systems. Supporting effective decision means most often the push towards automation or automation support. ** Enterprise data science supports effective and efficient decisions within a company’s value chain. **</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Challenges in B2B machine learning / AI</title><link href="/post/2019/12/01/Challanges_in_B2B_AI.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Challenges in B2B machine learning / AI" /><published>2019-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/post/2019/12/01/Challanges_in_B2B_AI</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/2019/12/01/Challanges_in_B2B_AI.html">&lt;p&gt;Applying and designing machine learning / AI models in a B2B context is often a challenging task. Methods and algorithms used within the context of B2C applications are often not suitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two significant differences are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;you have to deal with fewer data points, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the processes have often more human touch points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here some remarks on how to tackle this challenge towards machine learning and AI within B2B processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning Challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within existing B2B processes, we often obtain data points, on which you should not try to learn a machine learning kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem arises in the fact that existing (as-is) processes are often not designed for machine learning or automation. Instead many processes come with too many exceptions and intervention possibilities and are linked to outdated IT systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever possible, you should train your machine learning models towards to-be processes, not on as-is status. The goal is to push the boundaries of B2B towards new and better processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some guiding principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It is a path from analytics to machine learning and stronger linked to business / digital transformation. Applying machine learning comes most often with changes in the underlying processes and IT infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Data in B2B business processes are often limited, at least when comparing to B2C. Data augmentation techniques (simulation, re-sampling, digital twin techniques) is mandatory to design machine learning B2B models, especially when the future process is not yet stable&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Feature construction techniques is often a must-have due to important domain know-how inclusion. Proper feature construction methods often lead to insights for simpler analytical models solving the business problem with less maintenance burden.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence Challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI is defined here as cognitive AI and is also different within the context of B2B processes. Only one example here, not discussing the broad field of vision recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When designing a chatbot, e.g. for ERP interaction, you cannot train on a general corpus. You have to embed domain-specific terminology while collecting a significant number of training samples can only be done with the support of domain experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge I see currently is the lack of good tool support and integration ideas towards enterprise systems. Most tools are focusing on B2C flows which are useful to handle the massive amount of customer calls but not specific B2B processes with less data points. Most of the designs require semi-supervised support with immediate feedback of the user and with guidance or re-labelling of experts. These techniques are sometimes called an expert or (hybrid) crowd-sourcing interface with goal to assist the active learning. Active learning techniques are not yet present in current ERP systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I see vast potential in linking core ERP data and B2B processes to cognitive interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="B2B" /><summary type="html">Applying and designing machine learning / AI models in a B2B context is often a challenging task. Methods and algorithms used within the context of B2C applications are often not suitable. The two significant differences are: you have to deal with fewer data points, and the processes have often more human touch points. Here some remarks on how to tackle this challenge towards machine learning and AI within B2B processes. Machine Learning Challenge: Within existing B2B processes, we often obtain data points, on which you should not try to learn a machine learning kernel. The problem arises in the fact that existing (as-is) processes are often not designed for machine learning or automation. Instead many processes come with too many exceptions and intervention possibilities and are linked to outdated IT systems. Whenever possible, you should train your machine learning models towards to-be processes, not on as-is status. The goal is to push the boundaries of B2B towards new and better processes. Some guiding principles: It is a path from analytics to machine learning and stronger linked to business / digital transformation. Applying machine learning comes most often with changes in the underlying processes and IT infrastructure. Data in B2B business processes are often limited, at least when comparing to B2C. Data augmentation techniques (simulation, re-sampling, digital twin techniques) is mandatory to design machine learning B2B models, especially when the future process is not yet stable Feature construction techniques is often a must-have due to important domain know-how inclusion. Proper feature construction methods often lead to insights for simpler analytical models solving the business problem with less maintenance burden. Artificial intelligence Challenge: AI is defined here as cognitive AI and is also different within the context of B2B processes. Only one example here, not discussing the broad field of vision recognition. When designing a chatbot, e.g. for ERP interaction, you cannot train on a general corpus. You have to embed domain-specific terminology while collecting a significant number of training samples can only be done with the support of domain experts. The challenge I see currently is the lack of good tool support and integration ideas towards enterprise systems. Most tools are focusing on B2C flows which are useful to handle the massive amount of customer calls but not specific B2B processes with less data points. Most of the designs require semi-supervised support with immediate feedback of the user and with guidance or re-labelling of experts. These techniques are sometimes called an expert or (hybrid) crowd-sourcing interface with goal to assist the active learning. Active learning techniques are not yet present in current ERP systems. However, I see vast potential in linking core ERP data and B2B processes to cognitive interfaces.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AI Visualization / Explanation</title><link href="/post/2019/11/01/VisualExplanation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI Visualization / Explanation" /><published>2019-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/post/2019/11/01/VisualExplanation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/2019/11/01/VisualExplanation.html">&lt;p&gt;Visualization techniques are of high importance in the field of data science and teaching to explain the concepts of AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using charts, graphs, and animations to visualize complex topics is easier than poring over spreadsheets or reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, in this article, I started to collect excellent animations explaining parts within the complex world of artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sure many good links are missing, feel free to send comments, I will update the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to the original and creative authors! Great piece of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;intro-to-ml--bias-variance&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.r2d3.us/visual-intro-to-machine-learning-part-1/&quot;&gt;Intro to ML &amp;amp; Bias-Variance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/0.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visualizing-cnns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scs.ryerson.ca/~aharley/vis/conv/flat.html&quot;&gt;Visualizing CNNs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/CNN_number_visualization.png&quot; alt=&quot;CNN visualization&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;teachable-machines-and-many-more-examples&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://js.tensorflow.org/&quot;&gt;Teachable Machines (and many more examples)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/teachable_machines.png&quot; alt=&quot;Teachable Machines&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;explaining-neural-nets&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://playground.tensorflow.org&quot;&gt;Explaining Neural Nets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/explaining_neural_nets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Explaining Neural Nets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;explaining-gans-generative-adversarial-networks-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://poloclub.github.io/ganlab/&quot;&gt;Explaining GANs (Generative adversarial networks )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/explaining_gans.png&quot; alt=&quot;Explaining GANs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;distill---communicate-science&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://distill.pub/&quot;&gt;Distill - communicate science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the goal to best communicate science and serve the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/explaining_distill.png&quot; alt=&quot;Explaining Research&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tensorspace-3d&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tensorspace.org&quot;&gt;TensorSpace: 3D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;visualization framework for neural nets
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/explaining_tensor_space.png&quot; alt=&quot;Explaining tensor space&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="VisualAnalytics" /><summary type="html">Visualization techniques are of high importance in the field of data science and teaching to explain the concepts of AI. Using charts, graphs, and animations to visualize complex topics is easier than poring over spreadsheets or reports. Here, in this article, I started to collect excellent animations explaining parts within the complex world of artificial intelligence. For sure many good links are missing, feel free to send comments, I will update the list. Many thanks to the original and creative authors! Great piece of work. Intro to ML &amp;amp; Bias-Variance Visualizing CNNs Teachable Machines (and many more examples) Explaining Neural Nets Explaining GANs (Generative adversarial networks ) Distill - communicate science With the goal to best communicate science and serve the reader. TensorSpace: 3D visualization framework for neural nets</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Micro-services and its link to customer value</title><link href="/post/2019/07/01/MicroServices.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Micro-services and its link to customer value" /><published>2019-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/post/2019/07/01/MicroServices</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/2019/07/01/MicroServices.html">&lt;p&gt;When writing this article and during my daily work, I often have the challenge to communicate and explain different topics. Sometimes it is challenging to explaining low-level technical aspects to high-level managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is an attempt, and I will bounce in wordings and argumentation between technology language and business language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a thin line between explaining something and a bare listing of buzzwords, at least I try to define some expressions concerning my point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the age of digital transformation, a significant change within enterprise IT Infrastructure will take place. Micro-services will play a vital role in serving the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, digital transformation describes all enterprise activities to leverage customer value by utilizing data in a prioritized way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concise definition already shows the complexity behind the expression of digital transformation. Sooner or later, it covers all the activities of our daily work, at least every task which generates data or consumes data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An enterprise is defined as any human endeavor involving people, its purpose to serve a customer, where various kinds of platforms support each activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The customer value describes the heart of an enterprise objective while delivering the value is often done via services and products affecting humans and their environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term data covers all digitalized information mostly managed via IT infrastructure appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a technology perspective, digital transformation is the path towards data-centric decision making resulting in data-centric value delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the endeavor of a digital transformation, a significant change within enterprise IT Infrastructure will take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micro-Services will play a significant role in the restructuring of the overall IT architecture. The change will have benefits for developers as well for the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The significant change is the grouping around services instead of libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A service has a link to a customer need, while a (software) library is typically defined as a collection of functional (software) packages made generally available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a (micro-) service should fulfill a customer need (internal or external), and its design is managed and owned by joint development and operation teams with an active link to business units. The business units have to review their value regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we can see the link to organization design and the consequences behind it. The technical terminology is often linked to the DevOps movements; for the top-level management, it is the question of organizational design and who is responsible for building and managing a (digital) customer service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is all about purpose /value grouping instead of identical skill /functional grouping!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, when discussing (technical) artifacts with practitioners or top managers, only the terminology changes, the purpose should remain the same — delivering value to customer’s needs, independent of internal or external customers, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="MicroService" /><category term="DigitalTransformation" /><summary type="html">When writing this article and during my daily work, I often have the challenge to communicate and explain different topics. Sometimes it is challenging to explaining low-level technical aspects to high-level managers. This article is an attempt, and I will bounce in wordings and argumentation between technology language and business language. It is a thin line between explaining something and a bare listing of buzzwords, at least I try to define some expressions concerning my point of view. Within the age of digital transformation, a significant change within enterprise IT Infrastructure will take place. Micro-services will play a vital role in serving the customer. Here, digital transformation describes all enterprise activities to leverage customer value by utilizing data in a prioritized way. This concise definition already shows the complexity behind the expression of digital transformation. Sooner or later, it covers all the activities of our daily work, at least every task which generates data or consumes data. An enterprise is defined as any human endeavor involving people, its purpose to serve a customer, where various kinds of platforms support each activity. The customer value describes the heart of an enterprise objective while delivering the value is often done via services and products affecting humans and their environment. The term data covers all digitalized information mostly managed via IT infrastructure appropriately. From a technology perspective, digital transformation is the path towards data-centric decision making resulting in data-centric value delivery. Within the endeavor of a digital transformation, a significant change within enterprise IT Infrastructure will take place. Micro-Services will play a significant role in the restructuring of the overall IT architecture. The change will have benefits for developers as well for the organization. The significant change is the grouping around services instead of libraries. A service has a link to a customer need, while a (software) library is typically defined as a collection of functional (software) packages made generally available. However, a (micro-) service should fulfill a customer need (internal or external), and its design is managed and owned by joint development and operation teams with an active link to business units. The business units have to review their value regularly. Here, we can see the link to organization design and the consequences behind it. The technical terminology is often linked to the DevOps movements; for the top-level management, it is the question of organizational design and who is responsible for building and managing a (digital) customer service. It is all about purpose /value grouping instead of identical skill /functional grouping! In summary, when discussing (technical) artifacts with practitioners or top managers, only the terminology changes, the purpose should remain the same — delivering value to customer’s needs, independent of internal or external customers, respectively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Science - Best Practices</title><link href="/post/2019/05/01/data_science_best_practices.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Science - Best Practices" /><published>2019-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/post/2019/05/01/data_science_best_practices</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/2019/05/01/data_science_best_practices.html">&lt;p&gt;Data Science is the art to extract value out of data. I like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-industry_standard_process_for_data_mining&quot;&gt;CRISP-DM Process&lt;/a&gt; for data science work since it gives a clear structure and guidance for initial value case / prototyping phases. During my lecture at the Technical University of Kaiserslautern I focus heavily in understanding and living each step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, my best practices for each process step&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;business--problem-understanding&quot;&gt;Business / Problem Understanding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure the feedback of subject matter experts and key stakeholders at all stages in the process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Newer do the process alone you will do mistakes, the correct team / expert mixture is key for success&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use agile methods and never drop the review (quality) &amp;amp; retrospective (learning) stage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have always the next steps for automation in mind, never rush too far&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use and design for re-usable fragments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-understanding-preparation&quot;&gt;Data Understanding/ Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always start with data exploration phase&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do always a visual story telling on data to align and get feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store and clean data systematically&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each written code / result has to be reviewed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t move to fast into modeling, the full problem and data understanding is key for success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;modeling&quot;&gt;Modeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always start with a trivial model as a reference&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is no inference without assumptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start with small (statically relevant) data chunks, design for larger chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base model has to be correct all following steps will be derived from this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluation&quot;&gt;Evaluation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interpretation and understanding the potential gain of a trivial model will lead to the business case&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always compare each model against a trivial solution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand the outputs by all means&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start with a hypothesis /assumption in mind and check your result&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Link the mathematical model quality to economic measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deployment&quot;&gt;Deployment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start with full walk-through to the example&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visualizing results is key for convincing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always prepare for automation, pure non-reproducible power point means no learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be ready to delivery a result any time (automated / norm reporting at each stage)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, in this description the deployment results in a prototype or proof-of-value which does not mean enterprise ready deployment&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="Best-Practice" /><summary type="html">Data Science is the art to extract value out of data. I like the CRISP-DM Process for data science work since it gives a clear structure and guidance for initial value case / prototyping phases. During my lecture at the Technical University of Kaiserslautern I focus heavily in understanding and living each step. Here, my best practices for each process step Business / Problem Understanding Ensure the feedback of subject matter experts and key stakeholders at all stages in the process Newer do the process alone you will do mistakes, the correct team / expert mixture is key for success Use agile methods and never drop the review (quality) &amp;amp; retrospective (learning) stage Have always the next steps for automation in mind, never rush too far Use and design for re-usable fragments Data Understanding/ Preparation Always start with data exploration phase Do always a visual story telling on data to align and get feedback Store and clean data systematically Each written code / result has to be reviewed Don’t move to fast into modeling, the full problem and data understanding is key for success Modeling Always start with a trivial model as a reference There is no inference without assumptions Start with small (statically relevant) data chunks, design for larger chunks Base model has to be correct all following steps will be derived from this Evaluation Interpretation and understanding the potential gain of a trivial model will lead to the business case Always compare each model against a trivial solution Understand the outputs by all means Start with a hypothesis /assumption in mind and check your result Link the mathematical model quality to economic measures Deployment Start with full walk-through to the example Visualizing results is key for convincing Always prepare for automation, pure non-reproducible power point means no learning Be ready to delivery a result any time (automated / norm reporting at each stage) Here, in this description the deployment results in a prototype or proof-of-value which does not mean enterprise ready deployment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Homepage Examples - MathJax, and others</title><link href="/post/2018/12/25/Homepage-Examples.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homepage Examples - MathJax, and others" /><published>2018-12-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-12-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/post/2018/12/25/Homepage-Examples</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/2018/12/25/Homepage-Examples.html">&lt;p&gt;This post has the goal to archive some elements used throughout this homepage.
The static homepage is hosted on Github and is based on  ‘Jekyll’.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
It has been developed as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/themes/&quot;&gt;gem-based themes&lt;/a&gt; for easier use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a post with an article header overlay with a solid background color (#123).
Many examples can be found via the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://tianqi.name/jekyll-TeXt-theme/&quot;&gt;TeXt Template&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kramdown.gettalong.org&quot;&gt;Markdown (Kramdown)&lt;/a&gt; syntax&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mathjax-usage&quot;&gt;MathJax usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly everything depends on probabilities:&lt;/p&gt;

\[P(A\mid B) \; = \; \frac {P(B\mid A) \cdot P(A)} {P(B)}\]

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pictures&quot;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cost_function.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Animated gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;simple-tables&quot;&gt;Simple tables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Key Message&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.globalgoals.org&quot;&gt;Global Goals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;In 2015, world leaders agreed to 17 goals for a better world by 2030.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plotly-visuals&quot;&gt;Plotly visuals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;syntax-highlighting&quot;&gt;Syntax Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;foo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;():&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ow&quot;&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;bar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;emoji&quot;&gt;Emoji&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/ikatyang/emoji-cheat-sheet/blob/master/README.md
:robot:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><summary type="html">This post has the goal to archive some elements used throughout this homepage. The static homepage is hosted on Github and is based on ‘Jekyll’.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data science for personalized trend detection</title><link href="/post/2018/12/01/personal-tools.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data science for personalized trend detection" /><published>2018-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/post/2018/12/01/personal-tools</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/2018/12/01/personal-tools.html">&lt;p&gt;During my work as a data scientist I carefully follow the trends in the ﬁeld of artificial intelligence. This post describes one task I regularly perform to analyze the value proposition of different companies
&lt;!--more--&gt;
During the last years I collected data and the value proposition of more than 2k data science companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When playing with the data pool I do most of the time fast prototyping while working with new service in the market to see if they meet my expectations. In part, I have tested different Machine Learning Service from different providers (mainly SAP and Azure) for topic detection. As a data scientists I always try to combine a purpose (business understanding) with IT and machine learning know-how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since data science is more than machine learning I would like to point out the different techniques I used in the background for the rapid prototyping. Rapid prototyping or hacking is just like playing ‘LEGO’ - you have to know the right libraries / services. Please remember the rule of thumb:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;warning&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;from prototype to production requires x100 more effort&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data Science work should always follow a certain iterative data science process: value -&amp;gt; model -&amp;gt; evaluation -&amp;gt; usage. Otherwise, you get lost in time spent by falling in love with real fun - machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One overall summary of this snapshot: 80% of the time is spent for data crawling / cleaning. I changed my own business objective of this exercise 3 times :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business Objective (personal): always being up to with new data science trends, checking value propositions, and perform automated ,digital maturity’ test of companies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Crawling / Cleaning: I realized to my surprise that twitter and of cause ,&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;hacker news&lt;/a&gt;’ could be a good starting point to learn the latest trends. Most of the time I use available python packages (example description) for web crawling or a local tika server (launched via docker) to extract metadata and text from different file types (such as PPT, XLS, and PDF).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Model Building / Value Enrichment: Google geocoding API to convert raw addresses to Lat &amp;amp; Lng Coordinates, machine learning services for topic detection and translation service. One technique / library I like a lot from natural language processing is automated text summarization. Note, that all these techniques are using machine learning techniques to extract or enrich value information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Visualization: often I use Leaflet maps (see figure, only 100 locations), it gives me a dynamic mapping of company locations, their value messages and the direct link for more information. In the background I implemented search options to filter companies on specific topics ( e.g. Supply Chain + Data Science).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Usage: most of the time I explain these techniques in my data science lecture at the Technical University of Kaiserslautern. Additionally, in the last year I realize more and more the real value and great possibilities of the already cleaned and analyzed data.
For any questions or comments, just reply to this post or send me a message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;leaflet-example&quot;&gt;Leaflet example&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zoom out to see all companies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on location to see the extracted text from web Crawling (done in 2018)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only 200 companies are included&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;/assets/data/leaflet_small.html&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-python-snippets&quot;&gt;Some Python snippets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popup via &lt;a href=&quot;https://python-visualization.github.io/folium/&quot;&gt;folium&lt;/a&gt; wrapper.
Manipulating the data in python and visualize interactive maps via &lt;a href=&quot;https://leafletjs.com/&quot;&gt;leaflet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;folium&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;json&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;pprint&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pprint&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;folium&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;location&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;45.5236&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;122.6750&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;folium&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Marker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;45.5236&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;122.6750&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;popup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Mt. Hood Meadows&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;add_to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="BestPractices" /><summary type="html">During my work as a data scientist I carefully follow the trends in the ﬁeld of artificial intelligence. This post describes one task I regularly perform to analyze the value proposition of different companies</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quick Start</title><link href="/docs/quick-start" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quick Start" /><published>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/docs/quick-start</id><content type="html" xml:base="/docs/quick-start">&lt;p&gt;** This page is generated via Jekyll and the TeXt-Scheme **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TeXt Theme is 100% compatible with GitHub Pages and it has been developed as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/themes/&quot;&gt;gem-based themes&lt;/a&gt; for easier use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this document, you will learn how to &lt;strong&gt;install the theme&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;setup your site&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;local preview&lt;/strong&gt; for development, &lt;strong&gt;build&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;publish&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-mermaid&quot;&gt;graph LR;
    A0(Installing TeXt)
    B0(Common Method)
    B1[Ruby Gem Method]
    C0[Fork this repo]
    C1[Clone from GitHub]
    C2[Download]
    D0[Setup Your Site]
    E0(Installing Development Environment)
    F0[Installing Directly]
    F1[Docker]
    A0--&amp;gt;B0;
    A0--&amp;gt;B1;
    B0--&amp;gt;C0;
    B0--&amp;gt;C1;
    B0--&amp;gt;C2;
    B1--&amp;gt;D0;
    C1--&amp;gt;E0
    C2--&amp;gt;E0
    D0--&amp;gt;E0
    E0--&amp;gt;F0
    E0--&amp;gt;F1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-the-theme&quot;&gt;Installing the Theme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;common-method&quot;&gt;Common Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install it with common method, all you need to do is copying all the theme files to your project. There are several ways to do so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Clone &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kitian616/jekyll-TeXt-theme&quot;&gt;jekyll-TeXt-theme&lt;/a&gt; from github.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clone with HTTPS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/kitian616/jekyll-TeXt-theme.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clone with SSH:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone git@github.com:kitian616/jekyll-TeXt-theme.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Download and unzip the file to your Jekyll site directory.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button button--success button--rounded&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/kitian616/jekyll-TeXt-theme/archive/master.zip&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fas fa-download&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Download TeXt Theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you host your site on GitHub Pages, you can just fork &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kitian616/jekyll-TeXt-theme&quot;&gt;jekyll-TeXt-theme&lt;/a&gt;, then rename the repository to &lt;strong&gt;USERNAME.github.io&lt;/strong&gt; — replacing &lt;strong&gt;USERNAME&lt;/strong&gt; with your GitHub username.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kitian616/jekyll-TeXt-theme/master/docs/assets/images/github-fork.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fork&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kitian616/jekyll-TeXt-theme/master/docs/assets/images/github-rename-repo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rename&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ruby-gem-method&quot;&gt;Ruby Gem Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add this line to your Jekyll site’s &lt;em&gt;Gemfile&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;jekyll-text-theme&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add this line to your Jekyll site’s &lt;em&gt;_config.yml&lt;/em&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-yaml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;theme&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;jekyll-text-theme&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setup-your-site&quot;&gt;Setup Your Site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you install the theme with common method, you can go straight to the next step. But &lt;strong&gt;if you install the theme with ruby gem method, you have to do some extra jobs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With gem-based themes, some of the site’s directories (such as the &lt;em&gt;assets&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;_layouts&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;_includes&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;_sass&lt;/em&gt; directories) are stored in the theme’s gem, hidden from your immediate view. You need add some files in your Jekyll site directory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;├── 404.html
├── Gemfile
├── _config.yml
├── _data
│   └── locale.yml
├── _posts
│   └── ...
├── about.md
├── archive.html
└── index.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kitian616/jekyll-TeXt-theme/tree/master/test&quot;&gt;/test folder&lt;/a&gt;, this is a example with gem-based themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-development-environment&quot;&gt;Installing Development Environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to run them them locally, you need first install Ruby and Jekyll, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, run bundler to install the dependencies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--path&lt;/span&gt; vendor/bundle
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And also, TeXt offer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; support for development and public, this make it easier to setup environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kitian616/jekyll-TeXt-theme/master/docs/assets/images/docker.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Docker&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need todo is these 3 steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/install/&quot;&gt;Install Docker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Generate &lt;em&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--rm&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-v&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$PWD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;:/usr/src/app &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-w&lt;/span&gt; /usr/src/app ruby:2.6 bundle &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Build Docker image:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker-compose &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-f&lt;/span&gt; ./docker/docker-compose.build-image.yml build
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;local-preview&quot;&gt;Local Preview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; to start the development server, then you can visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/&quot;&gt;http://localhost:4000/&lt;/a&gt; to preview your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Docker, run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docker-compose -f ./docker/docker-compose.default.yml up&lt;/code&gt; to start the development server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;build-and-publish&quot;&gt;Build and Publish&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you host your site on GitHub Pages, just push the source to the master branch of your USERNAME.github.io repository, GitHub would build automatically. You can visit your site on &lt;strong&gt;https://USERNAME.github.io&lt;/strong&gt; several minutes later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you host your site on your server, you need first run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;JEKYLL_ENV=production bundle exec jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; to generated your site, then update the files in &lt;em&gt;_site&lt;/em&gt; folder to your server.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><summary type="html">** This page is generated via Jekyll and the TeXt-Scheme ** TeXt Theme is 100% compatible with GitHub Pages and it has been developed as a gem-based themes for easier use. In this document, you will learn how to install the theme, setup your site, local preview for development, build and publish.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Scientist - The sexiest job of the 21 centory</title><link href="/post/2015/11/01/Talk_data_science_sexiest_job.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Scientist - The sexiest job of the 21 centory" /><published>2015-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/post/2015/11/01/Talk_data_science_sexiest_job</id><content type="html" xml:base="/post/2015/11/01/Talk_data_science_sexiest_job.html">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science is the art of delivering value through data. The talk ‘Data Scientist - The sexiest job of the 21 century’ was given during my work at BlueYonder in 2015.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;extensions extensions--slide&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/JSoWYhivN4Wuex&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Frank Kienle</name></author><category term="post" /><category term="DataScientist" /><summary type="html">Data science is the art of delivering value through data. The talk ‘Data Scientist - The sexiest job of the 21 century’ was given during my work at BlueYonder in 2015.</summary></entry></feed>